# Tyler T. Mullen

Email: T\_mullen93@yahoo.com | Phone: 612-644-7902 | Address: 8916 Northwood Parkway, New Hope, MN 55427

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-mullen-94905553/| GitHub: https://github.com/RatofWrath|

Website: https://ratofwrath.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

## **SUMMARY**

Web developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science as well as experience coding sorting algorithms and a compiler for mini-pascal using Java. Currently enrolled in a boot camp for full stack development with MERN. Experienced in teaching end-users how to use technologies and working in fast-paced environments with demanding deadlines that require communication with co-workers and clients. Looking forward to utilizing my expertise in coding and troubleshooting to create web pages, applications and software.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Proficient with Java, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Firebase, phpMyAdmin, API's and Git Bash.

#### **PROJECTS**

LIRI Search Bot | https://github.com/RatofWrath/liri-node-app

- Allows the user to run searches for concert dates, movie information, and song information
- Uses Spotify's API to search Spotify's database and Axios to search Bands-in-town and OMDB's database
- Node.js, Moment, Spotify API, Axios, JavaScript

**Train Scheduler** https://github.com/RatofWrath/Train-Scheduler https://ratofwrath.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

- Adds trains to a schedule, displaying name, destination, and next arrival.
- Sends data to, and pull data from, firebase to display all scheduled trains.
- Firebase, Moment, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Gridiron Greats Trivia Game | https://github.com/RatofWrath/TriviaGame/ https://ratofwrath.github.io/TriviaGame/

- Six question football trivia game that the user has ninety seconds to complete.
- Upon completion, screen displays the number of correct, incorrect, and unanswered questions
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Crystal Collectors Game <a href="https://github.com/RatofWrath/unit-4-game/">https://github.com/RatofWrath/unit-4-game/</a>
<a href="https://ratofwrath.github.io/unit-4-game/">https://ratofwrath.github.io/unit-4-game/</a>

- Game where user tries to a match target number by clicking on crystals with a hidden number value.
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Back of House Team Member - Chick-Fil-A - Bloomington, MN

2017 - Present

- Cultivating strong relationships with co-workers and demonstrating a calm composure during busy and stressful periods
- Oversee food safety by monitoring temperatures and sanitary procedures
- First team member (out of 35) to complete a rigorous online training program set up by franchise operator.
- Train co-workers on proper cleaning and maintenance of deep fryers

# Technical Consultant - Allina Health - Minneapolis, MN

2016 - 2017

- Assisted approximately fifty Allina Health patients per day by recovering login information, resetting passwords, and changing account information.
- Knowledgeable in Allina Health's Patient Portal and MyChart, and explained features and benefits to patients.
- Created and processed MyChart user login for new patients

## <u>Intern</u> – *Lifeworks* – Eagan, MN

June 2016 - August 2016

- Relocated and rewired approximately twenty computers during the facility's reorganization
- Installed Windows 8 updates onto all computers
- Managed the personal login updates for all 150+ staff members across six offices to ensure they would not be affected by a recent security breach
- Effectively communicated with staff and executed the setup of IT equipment

## Wait Staff - Sholom Community Alliance - Saint Louis Park, MN

2011 - 2014

- Provided attentive service to senior residents by serving multi-course meals
- Assisted in pre and post-meal preparation and clean-up
- Aided impaired residents with basic meal assistance

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, currently enrolled

Augsburg College, Minneapolis, MN – Bachelor's of Arts In Computer Science, graduated 2016